Silence.
This is the place...
Look, we've arrived!
Yo!
Gen!
Xiaobai!
Sit!
It's been a long time!
GUESS
WHO
Hey, uncle and auntie. It's nice to see you.
Hi. Where's Grandpa?
In the garden.
Grandpa!
I missed you so much!
Ow, you're prickly!
Nice
To
See
You
Dearest
Father-In-Law
Long time no see. How are you?
Dad, thanks for taking care of Xiaobai.
Forget It
Just Ignore Me
Do you dress like that when going on a trip?
Yeah, why?
Never mind.
Won't you stay for a while?
We can't.
We'd be too much for the animators.
Sure enough.
Take care!
So you're Xiaohei.
Nice to meet you. I'm Xiaobai's grandpa.
And I'm her cousin.
Doesn't seem like he wants to bite me.
Yes, it's rather unusual.
Xiaohei's a very friendly cat.
Are there lots of mice in the big city?
Grandpa, he doesn't catch mice.
So cute! What's this?
It's a dumpling mouse, very rare.
So cute!
It really is.
But...
why do you have to keep it in a cage?
Because dumpling mice eat everything.
Anything but metal and living things.
They especially like wood.
It could eat the whole house.
How? It's so small.
Look.
Who thought it could eat that much?
We finally caught it yesterday.
Xiaohei?
Is it okay? They're cat and mouse after all.
It's okay. Dumpling mice are closer to rabbits.
Can we keep it?
No, it would have to stay in the cage all the time.
Sure... Or it would eat the house.
Usually it's very meek.
Gen! Bring the eggs!
But...
Coming!
Be nice to each other!
Is it done yet?
Not yet.
Do you want to come out?
Gen! Gen!
The dumpling mouse has escaped!
What?!
Where is it?
In that hole it dug...
That was fast...
Let's start building a new house.
Xiaohei?
What a long tail!
But is it long enough?
He actually caught it!
Xiaohei is its natural predator!
Gen! Take the table outside!
Okay!
Xiaohei, you did a great job today.
Eat up!
Eat some more, Grandpa.
Huh? It changed color!
Dumpling mice take the color of what they consume.
It's a sort of camouflage.
It's like magic!
But they are being hunted for their unusual fur.
Now only a few are left.
No way!
There used to be many in the hills.
That's true.
We should give it a name.
You'll get too attached and want to keep it.
It's fine.
What would be a good name for you?
Bi-dyuu!
I name you Bidiu!
If you had a dog, you'd name it Woof.
Xiaohei...
You're a spirit, right?
Thought so.
Don't be afraid.
You know...
I'm a spirit too.
Why haven't they come back yet?
Sorry for attacking you out of the blue.
I had to make sure you were a spirit.
I don't want to hurt you.
You won't hurt me either, right?
Will you behave if I set you free?
You little jerk!
Gen
What happened to you?
Nothing...
Ninja frog!
I'm getting revenge for you!
Ah, good luck.
Good morning!
We're gonna take him back today.
Why? Can't he stay here?
Xiaohei would keep an eye on him.
No good. Bidiu is too dangerous at any rate.
He belongs in the forest.
That's where he'd feel at home.
Really?
What are they saying?
I think he is fond of Xiaohei too.
But...
Give it a try!
If he doesn't like it here,
we can still take him to the forest.
Okay...
Don't take your eyes off him!
Mr. Xiaohei, do you want to eat some fish?
What about Mr. Bidiu?
Are you asking me something?
Lil Ji, are you all right?
Bro, Gen's got a kitty.
A duel of pets? Challenge accepted.
No one challenged you.
Big Ji's still the same, huh?
Yeah. He keeps trying to defeat me.
He'd get off your back if let him win.
I've been trying to.
Xiaohei, will you let him win now?
Darn...
The winner is decided.
That was fast!
Who said they have to fight?
Let's see whose one is more obedient.
Paw!
Why do you listen to it?!
Let's see whose one knows better stunts.
Our dog can swim.
Your cat can swim?!
That fast?! In freestyle?!
Okay, let's see, whose one is better at...
What are you doing?!
Ignore him...
Then let's see who catches more fish today!
You gave up early.
Shut up.
What did you say?
I will be back!
Why don't you just use your hands to catch the fish?
I could, if I want to be bitten to death...
I'm going for a swim.
Be careful!
I know!
Xiaohei, don't you want to be friends?
Where's the real Gen?
I am him.
I don't believe you. Did you kill him?
If you still don't believe me,
I can show you a certain place to prove it.
I want to get to know you.
I'm not afraid of you.
We're back!
We got big catch!
I'm heading out.
Will you be back in this episode?
Only during lunch.
I'll see you then.
Xiaobai!
Xiaohei and I are going for a walk.
Can you put Bidiu away?
Sure.
Hey, Gen! Heading up the hills?
Yeah!
Try not to fall behind!
Here we are.
You can come out!
A flower fairy...
Hello. Is this your new friend?
Yes.
You know I can't fake my thoughts if she transfers them to you.
You can decide to tell me about yourself when you can trust me.
Is this okay?
I'm not opposed.
I name you... Nimbus!
Where did you get that from?
Cute, huh?
Woof!
You snuck into Master Lao's realm? You're crazy!
What about you?
You both are.
Well, your spirit power really is extraordinary.
Yours too.
Coming!
Hello? Shan Xin?
Huh, you want to see Bidiu?
Fine, when can you come?
At the door?!
Bidiu
Hello.
Hoho, if it isn't little Sam Sung!
So this is Bidiu.
Yeah.
Nice to meet you. I got you a present.
Does he know what it is?
I don't know...
I think he likes it!
He ate it!
I-I-Is this okay?
He'll be fine.
His color changed!
We're back!
'Sup, Gen.
Hi, Shan Xin.
Xiaohei, Xiaohuang missed you!
A touching reunion...
Gen, you just got a whole lot funnier.
So, he can only be let out when Xiaohei's around?
Yeah, Xiaohei is Bidiu's natural enemy.
And Huang is Xiaohei's archenemy.
So even you have one...
Eggplant!
This is so cool...
Yeah.
Did he eat something pee-colored before I came?
That's his natural color.
How does it change back?
It reverts after about 5 minutes.
What if he eats something patterned?
No idea.
This is fun.
Don't give him weird things to eat!
Lunch is ready!
Coming!
Human!
Camouflage!
Shuttlecocks?
Why is there a row of shuttlecocks?
I don't know.
Keep calm! Our cover is safe.
No...!
Done.
What was that funny sound?
Come here! You three eat together.
It was just a nightmare...
What happens to Bidiu if he eats metal or meat?
Those are toxic to him, we must take care he doesn't eat any.
Then panties must be safe...
What?
Nothing.
Bidiu! Don't eat the plate!
What's that?
A box of shuttlecocks, it should be empty.
We just packed away a few.
Let's play badminton after lunch.
I'm in!
You shouldn't do exercise after eating.
We'll just swing the rackets a bit.
It helps digestion.
Stupid racket!
Xiaobai, give me another shuttle!
Didn't we just swap?
Serve is coming!
Badminton?
I am the king of badminton!
Racket.
Why can't I hit it?!
I will be back!
Who is that..?
You don't need to know.
We've exercised enough, let's get some rest.
Okay.
That's enough.
Was this a good idea?
Next time, I won't let you guys out.
What color he's gonna turn into?
It must be white.
He didn't change!
What did you give to him?
A broken shuttlecock.
What?!
Oh, no!
Spit it out!
What's wrong?
You two go to the house!
I'm gonna take Bidiu out for a bit!
Xiaohei, come on!
What's going on?
Oh, no! We're too late!
Bidiu!?
Get lost!
His weak spot is between the eyes.
I would hurt him with my power.
I need your help.
Quick!
Don't let him fall!
What's that?
Some spirit energy I left in the hills.
Your spirit energy? Then why...?
Bidiu!
Gen!
Are you alright?
Yes.
Bidiu!
He will soon wake up.
What happened to him?
This is what happens if he eats metal or a living thing.
It's one reason I didn't want you to keep him.
We must take him back to the forest.
No...
Everything was fine until now...
We just have to take care of...
The transformation shortens his lifespan.
And it's dangerous to both of you.
Let's take him back...
Xiaohuang is clinging more and more on Xiaohei.
Xiaohei, you'd better cherish Huang.
What happened to 'You two can't procreate'?
Why should they need to procreate?
Stay with me - let's walk on, kicking pebbles as we go
Stay with me aruite yukou ishikoro wo kette
Our destination may be whimsical
Yukisaki wa kitto kimagure demo
But with the scent of flowers in both hands
Hana no kaori wo ryoute ni
I’ll carry it to the you I’ve yet to meet
kore kara deau kimi e to
Wait for me — let’s talk, side by side
Wait for me hanashi wo shiyou kata wo narabete
Even if our first “hello” is a little awkward
Hajimemashite wa gikochinaku temo
When we open the boxes we’ve brought
Mochiyotta hako aketara
Let’s share the dreams we’ve packed inside
Tsumekon da yume wo wakeaou
The days when we can casually say “See you tomorrow”
Mata ashita tte atarimae ni kawaseru hibi ga
Are so precious and so fleeting
Itoshikute hakanasugite
Those feelings will never fade away
Omoi wa kitto kienai
We can’t catch up to the clouds drifting across the sky
Sora wo nagareru kumo ni wa oitsukenai kedo
But they’ll turn to rain, bloom into flowers
Ame ni natte hana wo tsukete
And surely, they’re calling out to me
Kitto boku wo yonderu